I'm gonna go ahead and borrow it, pops.
遠慮なく借りるぜ とっつぁん
I would like to show
Cut open my skull
Look into my head
I don't know why I'm so harsh
I could be so brash
I'm going to clash
'Cause I feel
I can always show
my everything to you
If this moment was for me
I try to hear
Lend my ear
Voices inside
One link to join it all again
'Cause I feel
I can always show
my everything to you
If this moment was for me
I try to hear
Lend my ear
Voices inside
One link to join it all
So it goes again
本字幕由诸神字幕组制作 更多字幕欢迎访问http://www.kamigami.org
翻译:死树懒 西西    校对:西西     时间轴:葛蔓     压制：娜夏
Your Hue is in a critical state.
色相が危険域にあります
Your Crime Coefficient is still fluctuating,
犯罪係数はまだ変動値ですが
さらに急激に悪化する可能性もある
but it's possible it could worsen rapidly.
#19 Transparent Shadow
If you don't address your clouded Hue,
これ以上色相を濁らせたまま放置すれば
最悪の場合…潜在犯認定もあり得ます
in the worse case, you could
be declared a latent criminal.
いえね…
Well...
I just remembered that my partner
fell into the same situation long ago.
相棒が昔 今と同じ状況になったことを思い出しまして
What happened to your partner after that?
その相棒さんは どうなりましたか
He stopped being my partner.
相棒ではなくなった
今は部下なんですよ
He's one of my subordinates now.
皮肉なものです
It's ironic.
ああなるまいと保身に徹してきたというのに
I've been trying my best to protect myself
so that I won't end up like him,
その結果がこれでは…まったく…
and yet, this is how it turns out...
What a joke...
I'll set up an intensive
therapy program for you immediately.
すぐに集中セラピーをセッティングします
I'll notify your office.
職場の方にはこちらから連絡…
Please wait.
待ってください
I can't do it yet.
今はまだ困る
宜野座さん…
Mr. Ginoza!
Doc, I'll manage to get by.
先生 やり過ごしてみせますよ
But I can't be responsible for what happens.
こちらとしては 結果に責任は持てませんよ
My current colleague... is a young woman
who was hired this year.
今の同僚…今年採用されたばかりの女の子なんですが
Watching her gives me hope...
彼女を見てると
希望が湧いてくるんですよ
...that everything depends
on how you look at things.
心の持ちようでどうにかなるって…
Professor Saiga...
雑賀先生…
Just get inside.
とにかく入れ
Hm? Hey, hey...
おいおい…
You're even carrying a gun?
銃まで持ってるのか
分かりますか
You can tell?
An old revolver... am I right?
古臭いリボルバーで　合ってる
まるで超能力だ
It's like you're psychic.
As I always tell you,
いつも言ってるだろう
it's the result of observation
and logical thinking, Kogami.
観察力と論理的思考だよ　狡噛
I think you all know by now,
but Kogami escaped.
もう全員に連絡が行ったと思うが
狡噛が逃亡した　疑問の余地は一切ない
There's no doubt about it at all.
はい
Yes.
He'll probably go after Makishima. We will, too.
やつは槙島を追うだろう
我々も追い掛ける
If you encounter the escaped Enforcer,
take care of him immediately.
逃亡執行官と遭遇した場合は　速やかに処分しろ
槙島は生け捕り
We capture Makishima alive, but we
take care of Mr. Kogami right away...
狡噛さんは即時処分
そうだ
That's right.
狡噛のことを考えるのは今はやめないか
Why don't we put
the matter of Kogami aside for now?
We're bound to run into him
if we drive Makishima into a corner.
槙島を追い詰めれば自然に再会できるだろう
槙島はどこにいますかね
I wonder where Makishima is.
His face is known, but
because of the aftermath of the riots,
やつの顔は割れているが
暴動の余波で　監視システムの何割かはまだ調整中だ
parts of the monitoring system
are still undergoing repairs.
完全復旧まではあと五日
It'll be five days
before it's completely restored.
During that time, we can't count on
facial recognition to help us investigate.
その間　フェイスレコグニションによる捜査は期待できない
Wouldn't Makishima disappear
and use that time to try and flee?
槙島はその間に行方を晦まし
高飛びの算段をするのでは
No, he'll definitely make a move.
いいえ　必ず仕掛けてきます
あの男は追い詰められて諦めるようなタイプじゃない
That man isn't the type that gives up
just because he's been cornered.
最後の最後まで　この世界を試さずにはいられない
He's compelled to test
this world until his dying breath.
システムに守られたこの社会に
He'll confront this society protected
by the system with blunt human nature.
剥き出しの人間性を突き付けてくる
そのつもりで
That's why...
Shogo Makishima made
a provocative call to Mr. Kogami.
狡噛さんにも挑発する電話をかけたんです　槙島聖護は…
色々あったと思うけど
A lot has happened...
大丈夫
Are you okay?
Well... this isn't the time
to feel depressed, so...
まあ…落ち込んでる場合じゃありませんし
I may not be the best person,
but my ear is yours if you want it.
こんなお姉さんでよかったら　話し相手になるわよ
そういえば人に愚痴ってないな
Come to think of it, I haven't vented at all.
Mr. Kogami...
狡噛さんが…
...becoming a real killer,
not just a latent criminal...
潜在犯じゃなくて
本物の人殺しになっちゃうなんて
I don't want that to happen no matter what.
絶対に嫌です
You shouldn't shoulder
everything all by yourself.
何もかも…自分で背負い込むっていうのは駄目よ
I'm okay. If you're worried,
would you like to check my Hue?
大丈夫ですよ
心配なら色相判定してみます
I was surprised when
I checked it myself this morning.
朝自分でチェックしてびっくりしちゃいました
Even after what happened,
it's a pale turquoise color.
こんなことになったのに　ペイルターコイズ
私　どれだけ薄情なんだろう…
Just how coldhearted am I?
Your heart and Psycho-Pass
are two separate things.
心とサイコパスは別のものよ
Then, what on earth is Psycho-Pass?
じゃあ　サイコパスって何なんですか
What is... a person's heart?
心って…
何なんですか
Hm? You didn't sleep?
寝てないのか
I had a hard time predicting what
Makishima's next move would be, so...
次に槙島が何をするのか
その行動予測が　なかなかうまくいかなくて…
So you think that man
is going to do something more?
やはり　あの男がもう一度何か仕出かすと
後五日で　首都圏のセキュリティーネットワークが完全復旧する
The security network in the metropolitan area
will be fully restored in five days.
刑事課の分析官から仕入れた情報です
That's the information
I got from the CID's analyst.
槙島にとって
To Makishima, that'll be the time limit
he has to launch his last fireworks.
それが最後の花火を上げるタイムリミットになるでしょう
コーヒーが入れてある
I made some coffee.
It's made from real coffee beans,
so it's really strong.
本物の豆だからめちゃくちゃ濃いぞ
Thank you.
ありがとうございます
お前が持ち出してきた資料には目を通したよ
I looked through the information
you brought with you.
I can see why you're having a hard time.
なるほど　苦戦するわけだ
雑賀先生の印象は
What's your impression?
シビュラシステム運営下に政治犯というものが存在するとすれば
If there are such things
as political offenders in this society
managed by the Sibyl System...
あの男のことだろうな
this man would be one of them.
Terrorists, anarchists, agitators...
テロリスト　アナキストアジテーター
...revolutionists with suicidal tendencies,
who aren't interested in the people...
民衆に興味のない　自殺願望のある革命家
The whole lot of them are all good-for-nothings.
何の道ろくなもんじゃない
By the way, what's the definition of anarchism?
ところでアナキズムの定義とは
支配と権力の否定です
It's a denial of governing and authority,
but it is different from confusion and disorder.
ただ　混乱と無秩序という意味ではない
That's right.
そうだ
It's denying an inhuman control system
and building a more human system.
非人間的な支配システムの否定
より人間的なシステムの構築
槙島はアナキストに近いが
Makishima is close to an anarchist,
彼ほど破壊を好むとなると
but since he likes destruction so much,
he's quite different from
the original meaning of the word.
本来の語義からだいぶ離れる
非人間的な支配システム…
An inhuman control system...
that is, Sibyl, isn't it?
即ちシビュラですよね
If I am to borrow Max Weber's words,
マックス·ウェーバーの言葉を借りれば
ideal bureaucrats are those
理想的な官僚とは「憤怒も不公平もなく　さらに憎しみも激情もなく
who intently perform their duty
without anger and fondness...
without hate and zealousness,
愛も熱狂もなく　ひたすら義務に従う人間のことだ」という
and without love and personal predilection.
In that sense, the Sibyl System
シビュラシステムは そういう意味では理想の官僚制的行政に近いかもしれない
may be close to the ideal
bureaucratic administration.
ただしそれは…
But that is, assuming that all
the known specs about Sibyl are true.
公表されているシビュラの仕様が全て真実という前提の上での話だ
Makishima told me on the phone that
he came to know the true form of Sibyl.
槙島は電話で俺に「シビュラの正体を知った」と言っていました
「お前が命を懸けて守るようなものではない」とも…
He also said it's not something worth
me putting my life on the line to protect.
Let me quote a little more from Max Weber.
マックス·ウェーバーからもう少し引用しよう
Bureaucratic administration
dominates the people through knowledge.
官僚制的行政は知識によって大衆を支配する
Technical knowledge and practical knowledge...
専門知識と実務知識
Keeping that knowledge secret
increases their superiority.
そして　それを秘密にすることで優越性を高める
Makishima is trying
to strip away that superiority.
槙島はその優越性を剥ぎ取ろうとしている
それはうまくいきかけた
And he almost succeeded.
例の暴動で この社会はかなりの危険ラインまで脅かされた
Those riots pushed society right up
to a very dangerous line.
そして厚生省から槙島に対して何らかの提案があった
And, the Ministry of Welfare
made some sort of proposal to Makishima.
だがその提案を拒絶した
But he refused that proposal.
一度録画か録音付きで
I'd like to talk to this Makishima guy once
その槙島という男と話してみたいもんだ
in a session recorded on video or audio.
For your research?
研究の一環ですか
He doesn't interest me that way yet.
It'd be purely to help your investigation.
そういう段階じゃないな
純粋に捜査協力のためにだよ
If Makishima was here right now,
how do you think he'd join our conversation?
もしこの席に槙島もいたら
どんなふうに参加してくると思う
He would...
あいつは…
マックス·ウェーバーを持ち出された次の瞬間には
probably respond
by quoting Foucault or Jeremy Bentham
フーコーやジェレミー·ベンサムの言葉を引用して返すでしょう
the moment you quote Max Weber.
Rather than a system, isn't it a huge prison?
「システムというよりは 巨大な監獄では」
Panopticon...
「パノプティコン…」
「一望監視施設の最悪の発展形」
...a facility that allows you
to observe everyone at once.
Sibyl is its worst possible form.
「最少の人数で最大の囚人をコントロールする」
You can control
the maximum number of prisoners
with the minimum number of people.
もしかしたら『ガリヴァー旅行記』辺りも引用するかもしれない
He might even quote Gulliver's Travels, too.
あの男はシニカルで歪んだユーモアの持ち主です
He's is a cynical man with
a distorted sense of humor.
なるほど
I see... he satirizes science and politics
that have gotten too advanced...
進み過ぎた科学と政治への風刺として…
そういう男です
He's that kind of man.
踏み込んだ質問をさせてもらう
Let me ask you a personal question.
君は槙島と自分が似ていると思うか
Do you think you and Makishima are alike?
理解できる点はあります
There are some aspects of him
that I can understand.
I don't know anything about his past.
槙島の過去は何も分かっていません
ただ一つ確実なのは
But one thing I'm certain of is that
there was a critical turning point in his life...
やつの人生には重大な転換点があった
自分が特異体質だと気付いた瞬間です
the moment that he realized
that he was idiosyncratic.
He can control his Psycho-Pass at will.
自分のサイコパスを自在にコントロールできる体質
それを「特権」だと思う人間もいるでしょう
Some people would
probably think that's a privilege.
でも　槙島は違った
But Makishima didn't.
やつが覚えたのは
What he felt was... probably...
a sense of alienation.
おそらく　疎外感です
In this society, if the Sibyl System
doesn't acknowledge you,
この社会でシビュラシステムの目に映らないということはある意味
in a sense, isn't it the same
as not being recognized as a human being?
人間としてカウントされないのと同じでは…
A child who wasn't accepted into the group...
仲間に入れてもらえなかった子供
I see... That feeling
might actually be the starting point, huh?
なるほど…
案外そんな気分が槙島の原点なのかもしれないね
とはいえ全ては推測です
That being said, this is all our guess.
本当のところは　本人に聞いてみるまで分からない
We won't know the truth
until we ask Makishima himself.
But you're not going to ask him...
君は聞くつもりはない
Right.
はい
When you're done here, come to my study.
片付けが終わったら　書斎に来なさい
I'll show you something interesting.
面白いものを見せよう
以上のように 狡噛慎也の性格と思考を理解し
Hence,
the ones who know Shinya Kogami's
personality and way of thinking
行動パターンを予測するに当たって
and are most suited
to predict his pattern of actions
最も適任なのは我々刑事課一係です
are us at CID Division 1.
Oh?
I see...
あっ　そう…
So how did it go?
で　どうだった
There's no change in our task.
われわれの任務に変更はない
狡噛と槙島聖護の追跡は
We, Division 1,
will continue to work on tracking down
Kogami and Shogo Makishima.
引き続きわれわれ一係が担当する
That's reckless.
無茶だ…
Missy and you both should
stop concerning yourselves with those two.
お嬢ちゃんも　それにお前も
もうこれ以上　あの２人に関わり合うべきじゃない
It has to be Division 1
一係でなきゃ駄目なんだ
俺たちなら　狡噛を撃つ前に投降を呼び掛けることだって…
If it's us, we can urge Kogami
to surrender before we shoot him.
Say, Nobuchika...
なあ　伸元
...since when did you become so soft?
いつからそんなに甘くなった
たとえコウが投降したとしても
Even if Ko surrenders, he'll probably
be sent to the facility and get executed.
あいつは施設に送り込まれて殺処分だろう
As long as we go after Shinya Kogami,
狡噛慎也を追う以上
we have no choice
but to put our lives on the line.
俺たちはあいつと命のやりとりをするしかない
だったらいっそ　三係に任せて…
That being the case, why don't
we leave it to Division 3 and...
And make it someone else's problem?!
人ごとで済ませって言うのか
どうせあんたも察した上で放っておいたんだろう
I bet you too realized what Kogami
was thinking and just let him be, right?!
狡噛が出ていくのを止めもせず
When he left, I bet
you didn't even try to stop him
and just saw him off, didn't you?!
指をくわえて見送ったんだろうが
あいつに槙島を殺させるために
In order to let him kill Makishima!
That's clearly a breach of trust!
No, in fact, it's a criminal act!
れっきとした背任行為いや　犯罪行為だぞ
口先でどう言い繕おうと
No matter what excuses you make,
you can't deceive the Dominators!
ドミネーターだけはごまかせない
今この場で犯罪係数を測ってやろうか
Do you want me to check
your Crime Coefficient right here right now?!
くそっ…
Dammit!
くそっ
Everybody leaves me behind...
どいつもこいつも 俺を置き去りにして
勝手に向こう側に行きやがって…
...and just heads on over to the other side!
あんたも狡噛も そんなに正義の味方になりたいのか
Do you and Kogami
want to be heroes that badly?!
It's not about justice. It's an obsession.
正義じゃない
執念だ
他にもっと賢い生き方があると分かっていても
Even though you know there are other,
wiser ways to live,
そこに背を向けたら
if you turn your back on it,
everything you have built becomes a sham.
自分の積み上げてきた全てが嘘になる
そういう瞬間があるんだよ
There's a moment like that.
Are you saying...
that that's your pride as Enforcers?
それが 貴様ら執行官の意地だと
執行官だからじゃない
It's not because we're Enforcers.
This is what you'd call a man's pride.
こいつは男の意地ってやつだ
Then, I have my own pride.
だったら俺には俺の意地がある
I'll stop that idiot Kogami
with my own hands at any cost...
狡噛のバカは必ずこの手で止める
誰が何と言おうとだ
...no matter what anyone says.
He's done for.
あれはもう駄目だな
ただ　今の状況下で即座に手駒にできる人材が…
But under the current circumstances,
there's no one immediately available
to use as our pawn.
Hm?
何だと
What?
Is that the final collective decision by everyone?
それは皆の総括による結論なのか
うん…だが…
Yeah... but...
Well, I can't fully understand
with my current capacity.
いや　今この容量では理解しきれない
いったんそちらに戻ってコンセンサスを取りたい
I'd like to go back there once
and check the consensus.
これは何なんですか
What is this?
古いタイプの匿名掲示板だよ
It's an old type anonymous message board.
It's operated via several overseas servers.
海外のサーバーを幾つも経由して　運営されている
海外のサーバー
Overseas servers?
If you look in the right place, you can find them.
あるところにはあるんだよ
So, anyway, they haven't caught
the Sibyl System's attention.
だから　シビュラシステムにも目を付けられていない
ここを使ってるのは　元大学教授やジャーナリスト　評論家　文学者
The users of this board
are former college professors, journalists,
critics, literary scholars...
They're the people whom the Sibyl
System determined were no longer needed.
シビュラシステムによって用済みになったとされた人々
They still comment even now
when their frustration builds up,
今でもこう鬱憤がたまると書き込むわけさ
saying things like,
"there's nothing good about Sibyl,"
シビュラなんてろくなもんじゃない
or "this part is so problematic."
ここがこんなに問題だってね
It might be fruitless,
不毛かもしれないが
but it's better to have
this kind of place than not having it.
こんな場所がないよりはいいだろう
さっき食事の前に１つスレッドを立てておいた
I started a thread before breakfast.
Ways to cause a complete collapse of the Sibyl System in five days?
This is...
これは…
They responded to my thread
by taking it as an interesting game.
みんな面白い遊びだと思って乗ってきてくれてね
They all look like stupid jokes to me.
どうにもバカげた冗談ばかりに見えますが…
ならお前が一番面白いと思ったジョークを探せ
Then find the joke you think the funniest.
お前と槙島は似た者同士だ
You and Makishima are alike.
Trust your inspiration.
そのインスピレーションを信じてみるといい
Leak classified information to foreign countries
Hm?
What's the matter?
どうした
If it's not possible to break into the system,
I think a good approach is to start by
breaking things that surround it."
To cause a collapse of the Sibyl System,
wouldn't the best way be to destroy
the food sufficiency system?
Something caught my eye.
気になる文章が…
The Sibyl System collapses
due to a food shortage...
食料不足でシビュラシステムが崩壊…
Hyper-oats...
ハイパーオーツ…
99% of the food
currently consumed in this country
「今この国の食卓に並ぶのは
９９％がハイパーオーツを原料とする加工食品です」
is processed food made from hyper-oats.
They're genetically modified oats
that have the ultimate harvest efficiency,
「究極の収穫効率を誇る遺伝子組み換え麦
and we depend solely on this single item.
ただ一品目に依存しています」
「多様性を失った大量の『単一種』か」
An enormous amount of a "monospecific genus"
that eliminates diversity, huh?
「なるほど 一つ致命的な欠陥が見つかれば
I see... If a single fatal defect is found,
it's possible that
they could be completely wiped out.
一気に全滅する可能性もある」
これが槙島の次の狙いかも…
This might be Makishima's next target.
Food self-sufficiency, huh?
食料の自給か…
Yes. This might be it.
はい
この手があったかと…
Crops, production system,
genetic modification...
農作物　生産体制　遺伝子組み換え
Do you have any information
on things like that?
その辺りの資料はありませんか
任せろ
Leave it to me.
Due to the sharp decline in population
and the completion of the Sibyl System,
人口の激減とシビュラシステムの完成により
人口の都市部への一極集中は歯止めが利かなくなった
it became impossible to restrain
the excess concentration of population
in urban areas.
But while people can move, we can't move land.
だが人は動けても 土地は動かせない
The primary industry of agriculture
was forced to shift to complete automation.
農地における第１次産業は
もはや完全自動化を余儀なくされた
Mechanized farming by Drones...
ドローンによる作業の機械化
genetically enhanced hyper-oats
遺伝子改良されたハイパーオーツと
and disease countermeasures
using good viruses...
善玉ウイルスによる疫病対策
こうして　完全無人化農耕システムが完成したことにより
Those things enabled us to achieve
fully automated farming and because of that,
agriculture as a type of occupation
disappeared from this country.
この国から農業という職種は消えうせた
今では北陸全域が人口ゼロの　巨大穀倉生産基地
Now the Hokuriku area
is a vast granary with zero population.
If there are problems
with crop health management,
もし仮に農作物の健康管理にトラブルが生じたら
hyper-oats, which are a monospecific genus,
will be devastated by disease.
単一品種のハイパーオーツは
疫病によって壊滅的な被害を被る
If the food self-sufficiency system collapses,
自給体制が崩壊すれば
Japan will have to once again import food.
日本は再び食料を輸入しなければなりません
他国に対するコミュニケーションを拒絶していたそれを
The government will have to rapidly
change their attitude
of refusing communications with other countries.
急激にあらためなければならない
With food shortages,
食料不足によって日本国民全体の犯罪係数が上昇
the entire Japanese population's
Crime Coefficients will rise.
Once they lift the ban on food importation,
食料輸入を解禁すれば
国境警備はどうしても緩めざるを得ない
they have no choice
but to relax border security.
難民の流入も始まるでしょう
An inflow of refugees will probably start, too.
Once that happens,
そうなれば　犯罪係数の測定そのものが無意味になるかも…
measuring Crime Coefficients
itself might become meaningless.
In order to make it happen...
それを実現するためには…
専門家の力が必要です
Right now Makishima needs...
今　槙島は…
...an expert's help.
I intentionally took part
in your plan to kill Shogo Makishima.
槙島聖護を殺そうとするお前の計画に
俺は意図的に加担した
その自覚がある以上
Since I'm aware of it, the next time
I get a surprise check, that'll be it for me.
次に抜き打ち検診を食らったら
それが年貢の納め時だな
I'm really sorry to trouble you.
本当にご迷惑をお掛けしました
Don't worry about it.
気にするな
I just got punished for burying myself at home
社会に参加せずに引きこもっていた罰が当たっただけさ
and not participating in society, that's all.
先生…
Professor...
お前に手を貸したことで
By giving you a hand, I feel
that I've fulfilled my own role. But...
俺は俺の役目を果たせたと思ってる
だが…
...even so, Kogami...
それでも結局　汚れ仕事は
狡噛…お前一人に押し付けてしまうことになるんだな
...I am dumping all
the dirty work on you, after all.
それこそ　気にしないでください
That, definitely, is not
something you should worry about.
For some reason, I can't even imagine
someone else besides me killing him.
なぜだか　俺以外の誰かがあいつを殺すってのが
想像もつかないんですよ
Mr. Kogami...
狡噛さん…
Inspector Akane Tsunemori...
「常守朱監視官」
「今から…」
I will now...
「あなたに全ての真実を告げましょう」
...tell you the truth about everything.
There's no way that I could love someone
But I want someone to love me
Even if yesterday could
continue unchanging into forever
You and I would never get anywhere
God... where did you go?
I don't hear any response,
but that's how it always is
Are you still here?
You'll never walk alone
I'll go with you
No matter the sin,
I'll bear the burden for you
I'll walk an uncharted path
All alone with you
A world where humans' state of mind and the tendency of their
personalities can be quantified. While all sorts of inclinations
are recorded and policed, these measured numbers
used to judge people's souls are commonly called "Psycho-Pass."
This story is fiction.
The names of all individuals and organizations that appear in the show
are fictitious and have no relation to those in existence in the real world.